# **ASHILD KUMMEN**

https://ashildkummen.github.io/ ashildkummen@gmail.com 07384672866 | London, UK



I am a MSc Computer Science student at UCL with a strong background in psychological research and statistical analysis, as well as experience in app and web design and development.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Regex, Scikit-Learn, NLTK, Matplotlib, Seaborn), SQL, MATLAB

(psychtoolbox-3), R (Tidyverse, dplyr, ggplot2, glmnet, R Markdown), HTML & CSS, Bash.

Software: SPSS, Minitab, MS Office (Word, Powerpoint, Excel), Photoshop, Windows, MacOS, iOS.

Other: Quantitative & Qualitative Research, Statistical Analysis, Version Control (Git), NLP.

Languages: Norwegian (native), English (fluent), British Sign Language (beginner), Spanish (beginner).

#### **EDUCATION**

#### MSc Computer Science | University College London

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

The degree covers computer science theory as well as practical software engineering, including teamwork with industrial and research clients.

Relevant modules: Computer Architecture, Database and Information Management Systems, Algorithmics, App Engineering, Project Management, Software Engineering, and Machine Learning for Domain Specialists.

**Thesis:** The thesis will be 3-month industrial placement over the summer term.

## BSc (Hons) Psychology | University College London | 1st (with distinction)

Sep 2017 - Jul 2020

• Received **Faculty Medal** as part of **top 5%**, in terms of academic performance.

Relevant modules: Machine Learning for Behavioural Analytics and Advanced Multivariate Statistics.

**Thesis:** Explored how irrelevant information can influence decision-making and the metacognitive awareness of such influences. Supervised by Dr Lucie Charles and Prof Patrick Haggard. Designed experiments and analysed data in MATLAB and R. Manuscript submitted for publication (first author).

- Awarded the UCL Henry Plotkins Prize for best undergraduate psychology thesis 2020.
- Presented the thesis for Lord John Sharkey, member of UCL council.

## Boston College Experience Program | Boston, USA

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

Introduction to Psychology (A), Introduction to Philosophy. Volunteered at children's hospital.

### Akademiet Sandnes Upper Secondary School | Sandnes, Norway

Aug 2014 - Jun 2015

A\*: Mathematics, Economics, Biology, Chemistry, English. A: Physics.

## Online Courses | Coursera

Jun 2020 - Sept 2020

- Mathematics for Machine Learning (Specialization), Imperial College London, 15 weeks of study.
- Applied Data Science with Python (Specialization), University of Michigan, 20 weeks of study.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Research Intern | Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience | University College London

May 2019 - Feb 2020

Involved in testing, data analysis, and pre-registration of research on language development and screen use in children 1-4 years old under the supervision of Dr Evelyne Mercure. Responsible for data pre-processing scripts to be submitted with the registered report. Manuscript in prep (second author).

## Research Assistant | King's College London Hospital

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

Assisted on writing and performed the statistical analysis of research on hardware failure in patients with diabetic foot surgery, led by Prof Venu Kavarthapu. Published in AOJ (doi: 10.21037/aoj.2020.01.06).

# Research Intern | Institute of Psychiatry | University College London

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

Wrote blog posts summarising research on the environmental factors influencing psychotic disorders supervised by Dr James Kirkbride. Received significant positive feedback on social media (psylife.eu/blog).

#### **COMPETITIONS**

### **UCL COVID-19 Recovery Competition**

Jun 2020 - Jul 2020

As part of a team of three, we developed an approach to mitigate spread of Covid-19 in hospitals with guidance from Dr Rebecca Pope from the KPMG Data Science Team. I created a 3-minute pitch video and designed and developed a webpage for the project. (Website: https://ashildkummen.github.io/traverse/).

Won 2nd place out of over 30 teams.